

Webb Lu

PHP Programmer

Kaohsiung, Taiwan

u.master.o.twn@gmail.com

https://uwaylu.github.io

中文, English, 台語

BACKGROUND

ABOUT

高雄人,PHP工程師。

大學時使用PHP爬蟲,獲取手機論壇的討論文章; 碩班期間以Matlab協作模擬LTE-A網路的資源分配;

服務於新裕豐文化時,開發官網客製化商品平台; 接觸了各種技術後,期盼能到較大的圈子參與團隊式的開發來討論、互相砥礪, 工作環境中能夠在同領域互相交流。

服務於聚泰網路時,協同開發行銷平台與設計金服系統, 能協助同事處理開發上的問題,並與前端工程師合作良好。

閒暇時,在家探索各種新奇及應用,如在OpenShift上架wordpress、Laravel+Vuejs串接印象筆記API、Discord 訂閱RSS資訊等。

2017年2月完成了高雄-墾丁百里騎乘,童年7月完成了左營單車挑戰百里。

2020年將終於基於vuepress的部落格上到github,規劃整理工作時的筆記,慢慢發布到部落格。

有感於自身在學習上過於依賴Google到的網路文章,缺乏系統性的學習, 2021年重新探索自我中,嘗試多方管道吸收新知,實踐發布到部落格。

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sep, 2017 - Aug, 2020 3 years

配合專案管理者協作完成需求,並撰寫文件

- o 開發金服系統,支援銀行卡、第三方支付、虛擬貨幣等多種支付方式
- 。 配合行銷平台開發,並整合第三方支付儲值流程

PHP Programmer, 新裕豐文化事業

Aug, 2016 - Aug, 2017 1 yea

- 。 引入Codelgniter3框架,全站重構、優化及修正頁面靜態化。
- 。 引入Vue2開發新購物車
- 。 引入Git,以Gogs架設內部版控;使用Gitbook撰寫文件
- 。 以pjax實現良好體驗的搜尋功能
- 。 最新商品功能全站架構與實作(批次上架、拖曳上傳圖檔、自動生成sitemap、採用中文網址等)
- 後台商品維護機制實作(批次指定類目跟隨特定商品牌價、商品資料匯出excel等)

SKILLS

Frontend Development

HTML Bootstrap

Javascript/JQuery

Vue 2

Nuxt 2

Backend Development

PHP

Codelgniter 3

Slim 3

Laravel 5

nginx

LNMP

MySQL/MariaDB

postgreSQL

redis

General Knowledge

Git

Linux

Markdown

Bash

EDUCATION

工程科學所,,國立成功大學

Aug, 2012 - Jul, 2016

數學暨資訊教育學系, Bachelor, 國立臺北教育大學

Aug, 2008 - Jul, 2012

,,國立鳳山高中

Aug, 2006 - Jul, 2008

AWARDS

第五屆全國大專校院資安技能金盾潛力無窮獎 資策會

Awarded on: Dec 10, 2010

隊名:「不要抓我拜託」

VOLUNTEER WORK

PHP backend, Mobile Open Platform Conference

May, 2018 - Nov, 2018

官網後端協助;年會攤位工作人員

Guide, Third IEEE International Conference on Smart Grid Communications

Nov, 2012 - Nov, 2012

Guide researchers and participants from all over the country to the auditorium.

宣傳股股長,國立臺北教育大學數學暨資訊教育學系系學會

Aug, 2010 - Jul, 2011

與系學會各股協作,並與股員共同宣傳系學會主辦之活動等相關事宜。

PUBLICATIONS

Uplink Scheduling and Power Allocation for M2M Communications in SC-FDMA-Based LTE-A Networks With QoS Guarantees, IEEE

Published on: Jul 01, 2017

Providing diverse and strict quality-of-service (QoS) guarantees is one of the most important requirements in machine-to-machine (M2M) communications, which is particularly need for appropriate resource allocation for a large number of M2M devices. To efficiently allocate resource blocks (RBs) for M2M devices while satisfying QoS requirements, we propose group-based M2M communications, in which M2M devices are clustered based on their wireless transmission protocols, their QoS characteristics, and their requirements. To perform joint RB and power allocation in SC-FDMA-based LTE-A networks, we formulate a sum-throughput maximization problem, while respecting all the constraints associated with SC-FDMA scheme, as well as QoS requirements in M2M devices. The constraints in uplink SC-FDMA air interface in LTE-A networks complicate the resource allocation problem. We solve the resource allocation problem by first transforming it into a binary integer programming problem and then formulate a dual problem using the Lagrange duality theory. Numerical results show that the proposed algorithm outperforms traditional Greedy algorithm in terms of throughput maximization while satisfying QoS requirements, and its performance is close to the optimal design.

INTERESTS

Others

Music

Anime

Reading